You'll beWITCHED! You'll beDAZZLED! You'll be swept into a
world of enchantment BEYOND ANYTHING BEFORE!
Bedknobs and Broomsticks is a adventure, fantasy,
comedy film directed by Robert Stevenson.
Three children evacuated from London during World War II are
forced to stay with an eccentric spinster.
The children's initial fears disappear when they find
out she is in fact a trainee witch.
Miss Price, played by Angela Lansbury.
Emelius, played by David Tomlinson.
Mr. Jelk, played by Roddy McDowall.
Bookman, played by Sam Jaffe.
Col. Heller, played by John Ericson.
Swinburne, played by Bruce Forsyth.
Bedknobs and Broomsticks is a 1971 American live-action/animated hybrid musical comedy fantasy film directed by Robert
Stevenson from a screenplay by Bill Walsh and Don DaGradi and with songs written by the Sherman Brothers.
It was produced by Walsh for Walt Disney Productions.
It is based upon the books The Magic Bedknob (1943) and Bonfires and
Broomsticks (1947) by English author Mary Norton.
It combines live action and animation, and stars Angela Lansbury, David
Tomlinson, Ian Weighill, Cindy O'Callaghan, and Roy Snart.
During the early 1960s, the film entered development when the negotiations for
the film rights to Mary Poppins (1964) were placed on hold.
When the rights were acquired, the film was shelved repeatedly because of its
similarities to Mary Poppins until it was revived in 1969.
Originally at a length of 139 minutes, it was edited down to almost
two hours before its premiere at Radio City Music Hall.
The film was released on December 13, 1971, to mixed reviews from film
critics, some of whom praised the live-action/animated sequence.
It received five Academy Awards nominations, winning
one for Best Special Visual Effects.
It was the last film released before the death of
Walt Disney's surviving brother, Roy O.
Disney, who died one week later.
It was also the last theatrical film Reginald Owen appeared in before his death the following
year on November 5, 1972; his last two acting credits were for television.
It was also the last film work of screenwriter Don DaGradi before
his retirement in 1970 and death on August 4, 1991.
In 1996, the film was restored with most of the
deleted material re-inserted back into it.
A stage musical adaptation of it had its world premiere at the Theatre Royal in Newcastle upon
Tyne on 14 August 2021 before embarking on a UK and Ireland tour until May 2022.
The film explores themes of witch, flying, nazi, world war ii, knight.
The tone is lighthearted.